My name is Anthony Maddaloni.
I'm a professional photographer from Austin, Texas and I'm going to talk a little bit about the different types of film that you can shoot with a large format camera.
It's four by five.
This is a piece of black and white film.
Now black and white film you can still buy.
You can still develop it yourself.
So it's really very available, easily, easily gotten.
The other types of film that you can use with a 4x5 camera are color print film and chrome film, and this is where it gets kind of interesting because if you look compared to a modern day digital print, color print, even a very high end one compared to a print that was made with 4x5 chrome film, that's slide film, you're going to see differences.
Some of them are subtle and some of them are not so subtle.
And that's one thing that really interests me as a photographer is what is it.
What makes the difference?
And it's not really so much of a better or worse it's just the difference and that's what is very interesting to me.
One other thing that is interesting to point out that if you are going to shoot slide film or chrome film, sometimes it's referred to as E6 process film.
You want to make sure your exposure is absolutely correct.
Slide film there's really no latitude for over or under exposing and that's a really important thing to know because one it's pretty expensive so you don't want to go through a whole bunch of film.
You're going to lose some money.
So you want to have a nice meter, a nice system of making an exposure that's going to be correct and everything will really work out for you.
The other thing about chrome film, color film is that you might want to keep it in the fridge.
That's a really good place.
If it gets hot you're going to have a shift meaning your film has essentially gone bad.
So that's some of the types of film that you can use with a 4x5 camera.